[Music]
hardly anyone can dispute that james
cameron's avatar changed the 3d cinema
experience forever when it was released
over 11 years ago
many thought the franchise was dead
until recently but behind the scenes
they've been busy all these years
working on sequels if all goes as
planned we will get the sequel to the
officially
most successful movie of the time next
year in december in order to make sure
you don't lose track of things until
then
we have compiled the most important
information about avatar 2
and today we would like to give you
loads of reasons why we're looking
forward to this mega blockbuster
however before we get to part 2 let's
rewind to the very beginning
after all what was the first part of
avatar all about this plot summary will
inevitably contain some spoilers since
we won't get into the storyline of
avatar 2 until afterwards
the plot basically revolves around jake
sully born in 2126 who joined the
marines at a young age
and was so severely wounded that he
became paralyzed from the waist down
actually not a good starting condition
to explore an alien planet however a
tragic
incident causes him to travel to pandora
instead of his twin brother
after triumph sleeping aboard a
spacecraft for several years he finally
arises on the beautiful and pristine
planet with a few other humans
and is briefed on the details of his
mission to mingle with the natives of
navi and discover their weaknesses
behind the whole operation is the
resources development administration or
rda for short they in turn are pretty
keen on the raw material on obtainium
which is found in large quantities on
pandora
since the human organism on the alien
planet is anything but
viable the rda has come up with
something extraordinary
the talk is about a scientific project
that has created a genetically modified
hybrid of human dna
and navi dna these so-called avatars can
be controlled by humans using their
human brain and any nerve endings
connected to the avatar
for jake in particular this is truly an
out of this world experience because in
this avatar body he doesn't feel the
impact of his paraplegia
and is thus capable of moving freely
already during his first exploration
mission however
things go wrong and he gets separated
from his group soon he faces a pack of
viper wolves and defends himself in what
should be a hopeless fight to his luck a
native navy woman comes to his aid and
chases the dangerous animals away
jake is immediately fascinated by the
beautiful navi who bears the name of
nitiri
he quickly learns about the customs and
culture of the navi people and finds
himself in a fateful dilemma
as the more he learns about nathiri and
her way of life the more irresolute he
becomes about his mission as a result
jake must decide on whose side he's on
as either way the fate of the usually
peace-loving people
rests with him now you should have
somewhat brushed up on your knowledge
regarding the first part as we mentioned
earlier
avatar set off a real 3d hype back then
which is why the film often has to put
up with the accusation that moviegoers
only went to the movies due to its 3d
and not because of the plot the fact
though that star director james cameron
has a lot more up his sleeve becomes
apparent when you realize
that the 66 year old has planned no less
than
four sequels for the franchise
let's now turn your attention to the
possible plot of avatar 2.
after the brilliant end of the first
part humans were successfully expelled
from pandora
slowly but surely peace returns to the
almost colonized navi and jake has now
fully become one of them
nearly 13 years after the first parts
and he has even brought off spring into
the world
namely his children nitiam lowak and
tuktiri
in addition to his role as a father he
now has a more laid back routine and so
he and his wife nathiri
set off to explore all the splendor of
the wonderful planet
in the process they not only find
themselves in the beautiful primal
forest of pandora but also in the
equally enchanting and dangerous
underwater world
in the oceans as to be expected the
human occupants do not surrender easily
and so they arm themselves for a renewed
attack on the resources and the
population of pandora
oh by the way producer john landauer is
sure that you will be able to watch
avatar
2 without any prior knowledge from the
first avatar movie
so it will not be essential to watch the
whole movie again
our summary of part 1 is therefore more
than enough
what's interesting is that even before
the first part came out director cameron
announced that he wanted at least two
sequels to follow
success proved him right with one of the
most expensive productions in film
history at the time and after the
blockbuster quickly rose to the top as
the most successful movie of all time
it became obvious that sooner or later
the sequel was to follow
planned were so-called back to back
shoots in new zealand for the respective
scripts of avatar 2 to 4 cameron hired
different screenwriters and designed
each of them
a film of their own that's how josh
friedman ended up writing part 2 rick
jeff and amanda silva part 3
and shane salerno part 4. only part 5 is
currently missing a screenwriter
james cameron who's certainly not a man
of few words also announced that he
would like to use footage from the
mariana trench
the deepest point on earth as a
reference for the underwater world of
pandora
in terms of 3d technology cameron also
announced nothing less than revolution
one innovation is to shoot the sequences
at 60 frames per second to achieve
better and above all
smoother 3d moreover there are
persistent rumors that avatar 2 is going
to be screened in 3d without the need
for glasses
and that would be nothing less than a
new 3d revolution
the problem with this is that it would
require upgrading almost every movie
theater
in the world to the new technology by
investing a large sum of money
a pretty unlikely scenario especially in
light of the pandemic
and the lack of revenue while cameron is
and remains one of the great visionaries
in the movie business
we can only hope that avatar 2 will not
only feature great 3d technology
but also a captivating plot
moving on to the cast of avatar 2. of
course several familiar faces will be
making a comeback including of course
samworthiness jake and zoe zeldana as
natiori
likewise joining the cast are sigoni
weaver as dr grace augustine stephen
lang as colonel miles quarage matt
gerald as
corporal lyle waynflete and giovanni
ripsey as park selfridge
for some of them the question is
certainly appropriate as to
how exactly their presence is going to
look like in part 2 because not all of
them made it out of the big battle in
the first part alive
much more exciting are the new cast
members though because as you would
expect from a big hollywood blockbuster
they are quite impressive
so far the cast includes vin diesel in
an as yet unknown role titanic actress
kate winslet asked the aquatic ronald
and michelle joe as dr karina moog addie
falco has been signed up for the
villainous role of general admore
cliff curtis plays the leader of the
madqueena clan jermaine clement becomes
scientist dr
ian garvin and david thulas shows up as
a new character named palak
all in all a respectable cast that'll
possibly be expanded by a few more names
for a couple of years already various
titles of the sequels have been
circulating in the avatar fan community
as is considered highly unlikely that
the movie will just be called avatar 2.
back in 2018 the british news channel
bbc brought up four possible titles
which even today have neither been
denied nor
confirmed so there are four titles for
the four sequels although it's not known
which title is for
which sequel the first one mentioned is
avatar the way of water
and could fit well to part 2 but also to
part 3 due to the water theme
after all both sequels are supposed to
focus on the underwater world another
possible title is
avatar the seat bearer this could be a
reference to the seeds of the tree of
souls as this is considered pandora's
holiest sight and was heavily
responsible for the complete
transformation of jake's soul to his
avatar body
the next title is avatara the token
rider
so far nothing is known about the so
called talking in the avatar franchise
but the term toku can be found in
buddhism meaning something like a
reincarnated person who passes on his
knowledge to new generations
in connection with the word ryder it
could of course also simply be a new
living bean on pandora
the last title is called avatar the
quest for ewa ewa is the deity of the
navy who connects all beings across the
planet and generally stands for the life
energy of
pandora thus one could possibly go on a
quest for awa in the sequel because
in the parts before life has gone
extinct in an
alarming way and the planet's decay is
imminent another possibility could be
that one must solve a certain task for
awhile at this point we can only
speculate
what do you think are the titles
credible and which title would you
assign to which sequel
feel free to discuss this in the comment
section
to the delight of many fans producer
john landa regularly posts updates and
behind the scenes footage on his
instagram account there you can see all
kinds of technically sophisticated
shooting work which shows various
underwater vehicles some concept art and
snapshots with actors in front of the
camera discussing every single picture
would surely go beyond the scope here
because meanwhile there are a vast
number of shots that are all worth a
look
in january for example we have the
pleasure of seeing a beautiful med kyina
village on the water
although unfortunately it was concept
art and not a scene from the film
another example from last october shows
a fully equipped high-tech
rda laboratory a final example from
august 2020 illustrates
quite well the immense amount of work
involved in shooting the mammoth project
as here you can see part of the film set
in a large hall in new zealand
all customized according to james
cameron's ideas of course
all the more excited many fans are
waiting for a trailer for avatar 2.
unfortunately there are no clues as to
when a trailer or
at least a teaser might appear but given
the theatrical release date of december
16th 2022
we may expect some video material either
at the end of this year or
the beginning of next year how did you
like a new video
write your expectations and theories for
avatar 2 in the comments and feel free
to subscribe
because our next preview video is coming
soon
for sure
[Music]
you